<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[dmaser@github]]></title>
  <link href="http://dmaser.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dmaser.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-08T14:33:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://dmaser.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[dmaser]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[git@gnarly.info]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a replacement for Google Reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://dmaser.github.com/blog/2013/04/08/building-a-replacement-for-google-reader/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-08T10:32:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dmaser.github.com/blog/2013/04/08/building-a-replacement-for-google-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As everyone knows, Google Reader is going away on July 1. For most people there are many appealing choices already out there.
For hosted solutions, <a href="http://www.newsblur.com/">Newsblur</a> and <a href="http://www.feedly.com">Feedly</a> seem to be excellent options.
<a href="http://tt-rss.org">Tiny Tiny RSS</a> looks great if you&#8217;re looking for a self-hosted option. I may actually end up using one of those. But&#8230;what if I tried
to write my own?</p>

<p>Now, I don&#8217;t believe that I can build anything better than the existing options, but I couldn&#8217;t help wonder, what does it take to build a feed aggregator/reader?
 And what would I do different if I built one myself?</p>

<h2>Design Goals</h2>

<ul>
<li>Compact view. I follow over 500 feeds. The last thing I want to do is scroll through them 3 items at a time. And for me, most feeds are more about the text,
than the images.</li>
<li>Less emphasis on social sharing. I&#8217;m more about scanning lots of feeds. Plus, I don&#8217;t usually know if an item is shareable until
I&#8217;ve gone to the web site to read the full content.</li>
<li>Tag-based scoring. Not sure how this will work yet, but some feeds post so many articles in a day that even just skimming for anything of interest
is nearly impossible.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tools</h2>

<p>My choice of tools is a mix of what I already know and what I&#8217;m interested in learning more about:</p>

<ul>
<li>Backend code: Java. I use Java at my job, so I see this is a good way to hone my skills.</li>
<li>RSS/Atom parsing: <a href="https://rometools.jira.com/wiki/display/ROME/Home">Rome</a>. I&#8217;m currently doing my own fetching in Java, but I may later look at the
Rome subproject Rome Fetcher.</li>
<li>Web sockets: <a href="https://github.com/TooTallNate/Java-WebSocket">Java-WebSocket</a>. Just learning and playing around with web sockets to keep the frontend up to date.
I&#8217;m not sure if it&#8217;s necessary or even practical yet.</li>
<li>Storage: <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/">MongoDB</a>. I&#8217;m relatively new to NoSQL. But since I&#8217;ll be dealing with a lot of JSON in this project, a document store seems
to make sense. I chose MongoDB after looking at a few other options because it was almost effortless to get started with it.</li>
<li>Frontend: plain old HTML, Javascript, CSS. At the beginning I don&#8217;t plan on using any JS frameworks. At some point I&#8217;ll probably use something like jQuery,
but while I&#8217;m still exploring how the app will actually work, I want to keep it as simple as possible. Plus it wouldn&#8217;t hurt to improve my Javascript skills.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Status</h2>

<p>After a couple of weekends I&#8217;ve got a fairly minimal prototype. (Code repo coming soon!) I&#8217;ve been testing with 4 or 5 feeds which produce a varitey of different
types of feeds. There quite a mix of which attributes a feed provider chooses to use. Some feeds don&#8217;t provide any content, only a description or comments, for example.
For the frontend I&#8217;m currently generating a static web page (with a tiny bit of web socket action added recently).</p>

<p>My frontend design skills are, let&#8217;s just say, somewhat weak :-), but I&#8217;m pretty happy with the way it&#8217;s shaping up. Here&#8217;s a sample:</p>

<p><img src="http://dmaser.github.io/images/prototype1.png" title="Early version of a Google Reader replacement" alt="early version of prototype" /></p>

<p>Right now there&#8217;s not yet any management code, so next few tasks will be tying the frontend up to the backend to start saving read/unread/new status and application state and minimal tools to add/delete/rearrange
feeds.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress Successfully Setup!]]></title>
    <link href="http://dmaser.github.com/blog/2013/03/30/octopress-successfully-setup-slash/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-30T09:39:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://dmaser.github.com/blog/2013/03/30/octopress-successfully-setup-slash</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was interesting. I don&#8217;t know ruby. I don&#8217;t know markdown. I&#8217;m a git newbie. Makes one wonder why I&#8217;m here!</p>

<p>It was easy to follow the Octopress setup instructions, but I ran into this <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress/issues/1138" title="bug">little bug</a>.</p>

<p>What&#8217;s next? Guess it&#8217;s time to learn a little <strong>markdown</strong> and figure out what exactly those git commands I copied really did.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
